

NEIL BRYAN S ABARABAR | PROGRAMMER

Location: Quezon city, Philippines Email: neilbryan.abarabar@gmail.com Mobile/WhatsApp/skype: +639972466473 Website: neilbsa.github.io/neilbsa/ LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/neilbsa GitHub: github.com/neilbsa

PROFILE

Pragmatic and highly motivated programmer who wants to solve problems towards to the output and goals using my skills and knowledge. With 6+ years of experience in programming, delivering results using technology such as ASP.net, .NET core, JQUERY, Angular and Nativescript for mobile development both android and IOS and also server technology like docker, IIS, kestrel for web.

EXPERIENCE

IT SUPERVISOR CIVIC MERCHANDISING INC. 2015-PRESENT

- Assess and maintain current companywide used ERP system.
- Attend forums and meetings to gather specifications and needs to the clients/process owner.
- Study internal processes, request, requirements and conclude with a plan on executions both systems and user.
- Teamed up with process owners and department heads to achieve requirements.
- Assess results and gather user feedback for possible improvements.
- Plan/Develop/test/implement new systems based on problem encountered or user requirements.
- Create and maintain cloud servers for the running systems. As part of implementation and ensure the system running 24/7

- Create complex reports based on management requirements using data from inter systems used by the company.
- Plan and implement data backups and disaster recovery using available open-source technologies

SERVER ADMIN

LHULLIER FINANCIAL INC. 2012-2015

- Create and implement server requirements for the procured systems of the company.
- Assess procured system and get user feedbacks
- Create solution for custom backups depends on system retentions or system requirements
- Ensure the health of cloud and on-premise servers in good conditions.
- Adjust security appliance for servers to be accessible yet secured.

EDUCATION

B.S INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Quezon City Polytechnic University Quezon city, Philippines 2008-2012

TRAININGS

Clean Architecture
UDEMY online course
2021

Angular Development UDEMY online course 2021

Nativescript Development for mobile UDEMY online course

2021

Microservice Architecture .NET CORE UDEMY online course

2021

PROJECTS AND ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Electronic signature

This project solves the problem of signature workflow. It has capability to record all the documents uploaded to the system, tracks record of the signatories, capable in capturing signature, and embed the signature as final report. It also has capability of organizing your files on the system using its folder management. It uses ASP.net in MVC with bootstrap framework and jquery front end scripting with MSSQL and entityframewok as ORM. It is deployed in IIS server.

Stock inventory System

This project is a inventory system used for monitoring marketing item stocks, it is capable in holding records product list and some distinct each product. it also has warehousing system that can totally integrated on product master to monitor warehouse level. It records all the movement of the item from Stock-In, Stock-Out, Stock-Transfer. It generates transaction reports, Reorder level report, stock status, warehouse stocks, Critical stocks, and Stock card.it is created using APS.net core MVC with JQUERY for frontend functions and MSSQL server as backend with entityframework core ORM.

Warehouse Processing mobile app

- It is build using Nativescript and angular. Its sole task is to process all the warehouse document such us Inventory transactions, Pick list transactions, Packing list transaction and transfer. It is used to update those transaction in Realtime while working on actual items. It is installed to a MPAD device.

Promo Ordering web app

- Its is a web application acting as an Ecommerce for my current company promotion products. It is use to take order on our events and also integrated to our ERP system. It is capable on tracking user contact details and confirmed orders. It can be integrated to our organization ERP system to convert is a sales order so we can process and make a invoice for it. It was created using ASP.NET MVC backed with entityframework.

Email Sender API

It is a small program, and its sole task is to integrate to your system and just to send email. With its interface implemented, you can send email with any configuration. It can easily be deployed on any operating system since it runs using .net core framework or docker. You just need to spin a server deployed it and binds its port to your domain. Currently it is used to our organization for our email capability needs to our programs. Specially on our automatic reporting.

Backup API

- It is program that helps to integrate to your system to back up file level. It can be integrated in SFTP, FTP as server. Can consumed using API call.

Examination program

It is a web-based program used to plan an examination for our recruiters in my current organization. It provides our HR to design, create, deliver examination contents monitor examiners, manage records, check answers gathered for the examiner. It also monitors the job posting and exam schedules. It is made from ASP.net core MVC backed by entityframework.

Warehouse Desktop program

- It is a desktop application that used to process internal warehouse processing using various external hardware like barcode scanner. It is used on processing Pick list, packing list, inventory transfer, inventory stock out, adjustment. It proprietary desktop app of my current company.

Asset Program

- This program serve as a monitoring for computer assets in my current company, it capture records for IT asset, compute depreciations, process warranty reports, Stock reports, Monitor user assets, record user asset consignments and approval. It was created using ASP.NET MVC backed with Entity Framework.

Angular Course Project

- This set as my training project for angular, it is a recipe app task is to record for recipe and shopping list.it is made from angular and backed by firebase realtime database.

.Net Core Entityframework for PosgresSQL

- This serve also my training project for .NET MVC Core backed with PostgresSQL using entity framework.

Clean Architecture for .net core

- It is a ecommerce website that serve as my training project for clean architecture approach for .net core back with different database such as mssql, mongodb, redis. It also run in a container technology like docker.Its is created using .NET Core MVC.

SKILLS

ADVANCE	Web development, C#, JQuery, Javascript, Angular, Typescript, MSSQL, PosgreSQL, Entityframework, Windows, Troubleshooting, Hardware, Microservice, HTML, Backup planning, Visual studio, Visual Studio Code.
INTERMEDIATE	Linux, WPF, GIT, CSS, Bootstrap, Materialized CSS, Kubernetes, Wireframing, Bash,
	Docker, Networking, Firewall, Nginx, Python, Clean Architecture.
BASIC	Project management, Shell and Dos scripting, Agile methodology

REFERENCES

Peter Joseph C. Rivera

Senior IT Operations Engineer Emerson Automation Solution peter.rivera@emerson.com +65 9113 8247

Laurel M. Litam

Former IT Supervisor CIVIC MERCHANDISING INC. <u>l litam@hotmail.com</u> +63 9154009328

Mr. Christer Poculan

Former Division Manager Michel Jones Lhuillier Michel Jones Lhuillier Financial INC. christerpoculan@gmail.com +971 506586940

Jigers Alina

Sr. UX Developer alina.jigers@gmail.com +63 9052826522

Jaime Balatero

Former Custodian of Michel Jones Lhuiller Al Aneeson Trading Co. Riyadh, K.S.A +96 6580 4459 59

I Hereby attest to the best of my knowledge that all the information above is true and correct

Neil Bryan S. Abarabar

Signature